What's going on guys?
I'm going to be going over a quick guide on how you guys need
to be handling proof of funds.
That's a common thing, a common theme that comes up with people,
they have questions about what they're supposed to say to a seller.
Thank you. That asks them for a proof of funds.
I'm going to pull up the resource document that we're going to have here
in the community. So the situation is the seller asks you for a proof
of funds before signing the contract.
And again, this is common. this will happen.
So don't feel like you have to provide proof of funds them right away.
We're going to show you, the course of action on how you can do
it. So, option one,
and the most common thing that we do is what we're going to say
to a seller is right here. Absolutely.
Great question. I'll have a proof of funds to you during the inspection period.
Here's why. As soon as we go under contract,
we start shopping to lenders to find the best rate on financers financing.
Lenders won't, underwrite or issue quotes until the signed contract is in place.
so, we'll need that before we move forward.
once we lock in the best option in terms of rate and everything,
we'll get a POF directly, from that lender sent over to you.
So what I always tell people in a conversation is,
yes, we're going to get you a proof of funds, but our lenders,
require us to have a property under contract prior to providing us a proof
of funds for that contract. So what we do is after we go under
contract, Mr. Seller, we're going to go shop rates at different lenders that we
use. I know it might sound crazy, but a quarter of a percent.
Or half a percent, makes a huge difference when we're talking about a multimillion
dollar loan. So we need to get the property under contract.
We're going to go, use one of our lenders and we'll get you a
proof of funds. So just as an assurance to you,
Mr. Seller, I'm going to add a clause to the contract where the
buyer shall provide a proof of funds within the inspection period.
I can either do that or sometimes I'll say prior to the end of
inspection period, a POF or proof of funds will be provided to you.
How about I just put that in the contract,
so that you have in writing from us that we're going to provide you
on prior to the end of the inspection period.
And then you guys, when you're talking to your buyers,
and when you find a buyer that's, the right fit for this,
you're just going to ask them for a proof of funds.
and then you're going to provide that proof of funds to the seller.
So this is a way that you can get out of having to provide
it on the front end. most sellers aren't going to disagree with you.
If you say, Hey, we have to have it under contract before we get,
a proof of funds for this specific property.
We work with them. And the last thing I want to do is talk
to a lender who makes me sign that I'm going to be working with
them. And then I get a better rate from someone else.
So I'm going to put it into the contract. You're going to get one.
It'll probably be pretty quick. but we just, again,
need to go shop rates. So that is how.
Are going to approach this when talking,
to a homeowner or any seller that you're talking to keep it casual.
and the more authoritative you can be with your response,
the better results you're going to get. So keep it casual and just say,
Oh, totally understand. Yeah, of course we're going to provide you a proof of
funds. Yep. we'll get you that during the inspection period.
The reason we do that again, is just because we need to go shop
the rates to see, which lender is going to give us the most beneficial
rates for us specifically. and as soon as we find that lender,
we have three or four that we usually work with and we kind of
shop, them against each other, create it as a conversation with the seller.
Like you're letting them in on the business a little bit.
Yeah. So as soon as we get it under contract,
full transparency, I'm going to go shop the rate to a bunch of different
people, and hopefully we can get the best rate possible by kind of pinning
them against each other a little bit. But of course, we're going to get
you a proof of funds. Why don't I do you one better?
Add a clause to the contract that says a proof of funds is due
by the end of, the inspection period. I'm going
you Call a bunch of different lenders.
Ask them, hey, do you work with, developers who build ground-up
development, specifically in the luxury space,
two million dollars and up? If the answer is yes, tell them what you
do. I'm trying to, network with more developers,
I have a lot of deals for them, I'd love for you guys to
be able to be the lender on the deal, they'll connect you with buyers,
but in addition, you can say, hey,
in exchange for you providing me a proof of fund,
I will push all of my buyers toward using you for the lending
services, and if you build a relationship with them,
they'll actually get you the proof of funds, but the best option,
and the one that works the majority of the time,
is gonna be this one right here, where if someone asks you to show
the proof of funds, you just tell them, absolutely,
we're gonna provide you one before the end of the inspection period,
after we shop, to all of our lenders, to see who can give us
the best rates. So that's how you're gonna approach it, and you shouldn't have
any problems with that.